<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>State Act Companion Program</title>
  <slug>state-act-companion-program</slug>
  <author>ssuslh1</author>
  <pubDate>2019-09-25 17:39:54</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2019-09-25 17:39:54</lastModified>
  <excerpt></excerpt>
  <content>&lt;div&gt;Just in case you missed it, the following Special Announcement was released from Signal on the new State Act Companion Company.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Effective October 1st, major changes will be implemented for the State Act Companion Program.  These changes are the result of an 18-month evaluation of the companion program.  The individual policies issued to Covered Employers are expected to have premium cost equivalency with expiring policies, subject to exposure and experience modifier fluctuations at the individual policy level.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Nationwide Insurance Company has been selected as the new insurance carrier for the program, stepping into the role currently filled by Arch Insurance Company.  Many of the benefits Nationwide brings to the table are highlighted below, but their selection as the carrier came after an extensive market inquiry which included over a dozen quality insurance carriers.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The benefits that will be delivered to our Covered Employers and Broker partners include:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maintain important continuity of claim administration through current adjusters&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Replicate benefits of concurrent and reimbursable claims and pricing infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Partnerships with high caliber State Act Workers’ Compensation experts&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Financial stability of Nationwide Insurance Company&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Expanded payment plan options&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved service quality and responsiveness&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Broadened risk and underwriting appetite&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Harmonized Safety and Loss Control with Signal Mutual Longshore Safety services&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Increased accountability&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cost neutral pricing impact at the portfolio level&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More consistent and transparent individual account underwriting&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Please contact us at &lt;span style="font-size: 11pt; line-height: 15.6933px; font-family: Calibri, sans-serif;"&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:Underwriting@SignalSafeShore.com"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Tahoma, sans-serif;"&gt;Underwriting@SignalSafeShore.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; or 877.215.1125 if you have any questions.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 700;"&gt;About the Signal State Act Companion Program:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Due to regulatory and licensing requirements, Signal Mutual is unable to provide State Workers’ Compensation coverage to its Membership.  As a result, since 1992, the Association has arranged for a companion State Act program managed as a fixed cost facility and available to only Signal Mutual Members and SafeShore Covered Employers.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 700;"&gt;About Nationwide:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 700;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Nationwide, a Fortune 100 company based in Columbus, Ohio, is a large and diversified insurance and financial services company.  Rated A+ by both A.M. Best and Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s, Nationwide is a leading provider of E&amp;amp;S and Specialty Programs with over $1.3 billion in program premiums, 40 diverse and specialized programs, and an average program relationship lifetime that spans more than 30 years.  Nationwide has been offering unique workers’ compensation plans for more than half a century and writes over $400 million in workers’ compensation programs and over $1 billion in total workers’ compensation premiums.&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories>
    <category>State Act</category>
  </categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>