<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Avoid these 6 submission pitfalls.</title>
  <slug>avoid-these-6-submission-pitfalls</slug>
  <author>ssuslh1</author>
  <pubDate>2018-11-12 16:54:31</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2018-11-12 20:57:18</lastModified>
  <excerpt></excerpt>
  <content>&lt;div&gt;Ever have a submission that seems to go back and forth with questions and never gets that fast, easy quote we all want and love?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The fastest way to get a quote from SafeShore is to submit online at &lt;a href="http://safeshore.online/Submissions"&gt;http://safeshore.online/Submissions&lt;/a&gt;. This online process provides us with every single piece of information we need when all questions are answered and all documents are provided.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Below are six typical exceptions, along with the type of information needed to avoid those additional emails and questions:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;New Venture or less than 3 years in business&lt;/b&gt;- Provide the owner's resume that demonstrates the owner knows how to do the work and has business management experience.  Business management experience needs to show they know how to “RUN” a business, not just manage a group of people.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;No prior longshore coverage&lt;/b&gt; - Provide Employer’s 5-year history (payroll, premiums, and loss runs) for their State Act Workers’ Compensation coverage.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;New to longshore or hiring new people&lt;/b&gt; - Need a Hiring/Screening Process to include medical screening in place.  This will help the Employer know they are hiring people that are capable of doing the job function.  It also helps in keeping from hiring “their next big claim”.  Read this blog for more information.  &lt;a href="https://blog.ligmarine.com/2016/04/are-you-hiring-your-next-big-claim.html"&gt;https://blog.ligmarine.com/2016/04/are-you-hiring-your-next-big-claim.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;High loss frequency and/or loss ratio&lt;/b&gt; - Explain what happened and why it won’t happen again.  The more details the better.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Working from heights&lt;/b&gt; - Provide a copy of their safety program to include their height safety.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Employees have exposure on a vessel in navigation and/or go out to offshore rigs via vessel&lt;/b&gt; - The Employer needs Maritime Employers Liability (MEL) Coverage.  We will either need proof of MEL coverage at binding or need to quote it in conjunction.  This link has the MEL application included: &lt;a href="https://ligresources.blob.core.windows.net/safeshore/SafeShore Fillable Application Supplements.pdf"&gt;SafeShore App &amp;amp; Supp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;Even if you submit by email to &lt;a href="mailto:Underwriting@SignalSafeShore.com"&gt;Underwriting@SignalSafeShore.com&lt;/a&gt;, provide fully completed applications and supplementals (&lt;a href="https://ligresources.blob.core.windows.net/safeshore/SafeShore Fillable Application Supplements.pdf"&gt;SafeShore App &amp;amp; Supp&lt;/a&gt;), currently valued loss runs for 5 years, a copy of the mod worksheet (if available) and any of the above items that will help move the account along.  We pride ourselves on knowing our accounts, so we need your help to get to know yours. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>