<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>What are Recreational Vessels?</title>
  <slug>what-are-recreational-vessels</slug>
  <author>ssuslh1</author>
  <pubDate>2019-09-25 17:34:32</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2019-09-25 17:43:59</lastModified>
  <excerpt></excerpt>
  <content>&lt;img src="/posts/files/093d58b3-4cf7-40f2-8663-90c06d6c3804.jpeg" alt=""  /&gt;&lt;div&gt;What is a recreational vessel in the eyes of the Longshore Act?  We may think it is any vessel being manufactured or operated primarily for pleasure or leased, rented or chartered to another for the latter’s pleasure.  So, that means all recreational vessel repair/service work (and building under 65 feet) is all state act, right?  Well, not necessarily.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;When the recreational reform in 2009 was published, many people read it as all recreational repair and service work and building under 65 feet was all state act.  This included things like all mega yachts, all skipper charters, all bareboat charters, etc.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In 2012, the clarifying rules were published:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:700"&gt;Recreational Vessels – Repair/Service Exempt from Longshore&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bareboat Charters 12 or fewer passengers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Passenger vessels and submersibles with no “passengers for hire” (but NOT ferries) 100% pleasure use&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Federal, State or Local Government Vessels&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Not more than “infrequent” commercial use&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:700"&gt;Commercial Vessels – Repair/Service Subject to Longshore&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;All Ferry Boats&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;All Skippered Charter&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;All Passenger carrying vessels and submersibles with at least one passenger for hire&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bareboat charter over 12 people&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Commercial use &amp;amp; military vessels&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;One of the most commonly misclassed vessels under the recreational definition are mega yachts.  The vast majority of mega yachts are chartered with crew.  Meaning, it fits the commercial vessel definition under the Longshore Law and therefore repair and service of a mega yacht is Longshore work!  How many accounts do you currently write that work on Mega Yachts and have everything classed as state act?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;For more information on “What is a recreational vessel?”, you can review the Longshore Regulations at &lt;a href="https://aviaf.us12.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c195001e2314d2f4aa3e3b8ec&amp;amp;id=7ba1526176&amp;amp;e=65e09c56ae"&gt;§ 701.501&lt;/a&gt; and also watch this video that explains it further, &lt;a href="https://aviaf.us12.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c195001e2314d2f4aa3e3b8ec&amp;amp;id=580e312284&amp;amp;e=65e09c56ae"&gt;2012 Recreational Vessel Definition Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>