<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Subcontractors</title>
  <slug>subcontractors</slug>
  <author>ssuslh1</author>
  <pubDate>2018-08-17 18:48:19</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2018-08-17 18:48:19</lastModified>
  <excerpt></excerpt>
  <content>&lt;div&gt;Did you know that if your Covered Employer has uninsured subcontractors working for them, THEY pick up their exposure?  And if the subcontractor doesn’t have the proper coverage in place, ie Longshore, it is now THE EMPLOYER’S responsibility?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;There are some issues hiring uninsured subcontractors:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Under the Longshore Act, the last responsible employer rule still applies.  Meaning, if a subcontractor, months down the road, is found that an injury was a result of working in the Longshore field, the claim comes back to them even if the subcontractor is no longer working for the Employer. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;No screening is done before the subcontractor is hired&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your Employer has little to no safety control&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Hiring uninsured subcontractors can also be an issue with the WC Carrier.  This may cause coverage to be canceled as coverage is being extended to people the Carrier never intended to cover.  And did you know that if the Employer is currently covered by a Leasing Company, there is NO coverage extended to the uninsured subcontractor as they are not named employees of the Leasing Company?  This leaves the Employer wide open if that uninsured subcontractor is hurt.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;How can this be handled?  When the Employer hires subcontractors, they need to collect, review and verify proper coverage is in place.  Review the certificate and confirm that it shows State Act Worker’s Compensation, the Longshore endorsement (or separate Longshore Policy), and Maritime Employers Liability if there is exposure on a vessel in navigation.  When the certificates are being checked and verified, make sure that the Carrier providing the Longshore coverage is an approved Longshore Carrier by the DOL.  This can easily be checked by visiting &lt;a href="https://www.dol.gov/owcp/dlhwc/lscarrier.htm" style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);"&gt;https://www.dol.gov/owcp/dlhwc/lscarrier.htm&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/div&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories></categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>