<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>How to File Claims</title>
  <slug>how-to-file-claims</slug>
  <author>ssuslh1</author>
  <pubDate>2018-08-17 18:35:53</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2018-09-05 20:29:15</lastModified>
  <excerpt></excerpt>
  <content>All SafeShore claims are managed and administered by Charles Taylor’s Third Party Administrator (TPA).  There is a team of claims managers and administration that are dedicated exclusively to Longshore that will provide Covered Employers with complete claims service.  Local adjusters are in place nationally to conduct investigations and face-to-face interviews with injured workers and provide other local services.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="color:rgb(0,0,0)"&gt;SafeShore has created a user-friendly web-based Claims Protocol, &lt;a href="http://safeshore.online/claims"&gt;http://safeshore.online/claims&lt;/a&gt;.  This website will assist in providing instructions on how to file a claim for Longshore, State Workers’ Compensation and/or Maritime Employers Liability.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A Quick Guide:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Longshore – &lt;a href="https://www.dol.gov/owcp/dlhwc/ls-202.pdf"&gt;Form LS202&lt;/a&gt; must be completed by the Covered Employer.  Once completed, a copy needs to be sent directly to the DOL per the instructions listed on the form and then a copy sent to SafeShore at &lt;a href="mailto:Claims@SignalSafeShore.com"&gt;Claims@SignalSafeShore.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;State Act – If the Covered Employer’s State Act Coverage is covered by Arch, claim details can be sent to &lt;a href="mailto:Claims@SignalSafeShore.com"&gt;Claims@SignalSafeShore.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maritime Employers Liability – If the Covered Employer’s MEL is covered under the SafeShore Program, then the “&lt;a href="http://www.uslh.org/MELInjury"&gt;Marine Employee Injury Report Form&lt;/a&gt;” needs to be completed in full and sent to &lt;a href="mailto:SafeShoreMELClaims@LIGMarine.com"&gt;SafeShoreMELClaims@LIGMarine.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;When completing the different forms, be sure that the employee’s name, address, phone number, date of birth and social security number are included.  This information is necessary for the initial contact of the employee as well as setting up the claim.  When all the information is provided up front, it makes for a smoother set up process for everyone.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The most important piece of information, be sure to report claims AS SOON AS THEY OCCUR!  There are penalties associated with late reporting.  Under the LHWCA, a claim must be filed with the OWCP within 10 days of the accident occurring.  Failure to do so can result in a fine upwards of $22,587 to the Covered Employer, which is &lt;b&gt;NOT&lt;/b&gt; covered by the Longshore policy.  For more info on Late Filing Penalties, visit&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.safeshore.online/post/dol-raised-late-filing-penalties"&gt;http://blog.safeshore.online/post/dol-raised-late-filing-penalties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;During the claim filing process, if there are any questions, Charles Taylor, TPA can be contacted at 203-210-1600.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories>
    <category>Claims</category>
  </categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>